Hello, English learners.
Welcome back to English pod.
My name is Marco and I'm
Erica and today with Erica
we're bringing you a great lesson
about time. You need more of it.
We need more time, right?
So we're going to be teaching
you how you can ask for
more time. If you're working
on a project at work and
you can't finish it on time,
you have to ask your
boss for more time. Right.
So today in our dialogue, Casey needs
more time to put together a press kit.
What's a press
kit? Good question.
A press kit is something
the marketing department
will put together.
Basically pictures, logos,
information about the
company. So when a newspaper
or a magazine wants to write
an article about them, so they
have something already
prepared that they could give the
newspaper or magazine.
Okay. Okay. So let's listen
to our dialogue for the
first time and as always
it's going to be at a normal
speed so it might be a little bit
difficult to understand.
Welcome back in one
minute and tell you about
some of the key language.
I've been meaning to
talk to you about that.
I might need to ask for an
extension on that deadline.
You've had over a month to get
this finalized. Why are things delayed?
Well, the thing is, we ran into a
lot of problems. I'm not looking
for excuses here. I just want
to get this finished on time.
I know, and I apologize for
the delay, but some things were
just beyond my control. I had
trouble booking the photographer
and then Michael was sick for
three weeks, so I couldn't include
him in the photos. And the
design team lost all the files,
so I had to redo the
pictures. I'm not going to put
this off any longer, Casey.
I want those photos ASAP.
All right, so Casey
is in trouble, I think.
Yeah, I think her boss
is pretty upset. Yeah.
Well, let's take a look
at some of the language
that we saw in this dialogue
in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
First word today is deadline.
Deadline.
So Erica, what's a deadline?
It is the last possible
date to do something.
So for example, when we
were in school, our teacher
would send us homework
and say it was for Friday.
So the deadline was
Friday was Friday, right?
Or when you're at work,
you have projects that you
have to finish by a certain
date. That's your deadline.
Exactly.
Okay, let's look at our next word.
Extension.
So extension and
deadline go together, right?
Exactly. If you can't reach
your deadline or you can't
make your deadline, you
must ask for an extension.
Extension. So you ask for more time.
Yeah, an extension is moving
the deadline in the future.
All right, interesting.
Let's look at our next word.
Ran into.
Ran into some problems.
So we ran into some
problems in this dialogue.
Let's listen to some more examples of
running to so we can understand the meaning.
Example one.
We ran into a storm on our way home.
Example two.
If you're not careful now, you're
going to run into a lot of problems later.
Example three.
I ran into some trouble with my computer.
Okay, good example.
So it's clear now, right?
Right.
If you run into problems,
you meet some problems.
Right.
Many students say it in that
way, I met some problems.
Yeah, but that's wrong.
Right.
So you would say I ran into some problems.
I met some problems is wrong, wrong, wrong.
Okay, don't say met some problems.
I ran into some problems.
I ran into.
Okay.
And our last word for language
takeaway delayed delayed delayed delayed.
So when something
is delayed, it's late late.
And the opposite is on time.
Yeah.
So your flight was delayed
or your flight was on time.
The project was delayed
or your project was on time.
There.
All right.
So now let's go back to the dialogue.
Let's listen to it again.
And this time it will
be a little bit slower.
So you can understand some of
these phrases we just talked about.
So Casey, how are things going
with the photos for the press kit?
Yeah.
I've been meeting the
talk to you about that.
I might need to ask for an
extension on that deadline.
You've had over a
month to get this finalized.
Why are things delayed?
Well, the thing is, we
ran into a lot of problems.
I'm not looking for excuses here.
I just want to get this finished on time.
I know.
And I apologize for the delay.
But some things were
just beyond my control.
I had trouble booking the photographer.
And then Michael was sick for three weeks.
So I couldn't include him in the photos.
And the design team lost all the files.
So I had to redo the pictures.
I'm not going to put
this off any longer, Casey.
I want those photos ASAP.
OK.
So there were some really useful
phrases that we saw in this dialogue.
Some wonderful phrases that you can
use when you want to ask for more time.
OK.
So let's look at these
phrases in fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
All right.
What's our first phrase?
I've been meaning to talk to you.
I've been meaning to.
OK.
We have some really great
examples of how you can combine.
I've been meaning to with different verbs.
Yeah.
Let's listen.
I'm poor one.
I'm sorry I haven't called you yet.
I've been meaning to, but I've been busy.
Example two.
I've been meaning to tell
you that John quit yesterday.
Example three.
I've been meaning to
see that film for a while.
I've been meaning to go to that
restaurant, but I haven't had time.
So you've been wanting to for a long time.
I've been thinking about it.
I've been planning to do it.
But you just haven't done it.
I haven't done it because I
haven't had time or money.
OK.
Good phrase.
Our next phrase is beyond my control.
It's beyond my control.
So it means that I can't control it.
You can't do anything about it.
Can't do anything about it.
The weather is beyond my control.
Right.
Or relate with this project because
Jane was sick for one month.
It was beyond my control.
OK.
It wasn't your fault.
No.
OK.
And our last phrase for fluency builder.
Put this off.
So let's listen to some more examples of
put this off before we explain the meaning.
Example one.
I've been putting off this project
for a week, and it's due tomorrow.
Example two.
Can we put off our meeting until next week?
I'm too busy right now.
Example three.
I've been putting off my email all day,
and now I have 50 messages to respond to.
So Marco, when you put
something off, you leave it for later.
OK.
Right.
So maybe I have to write a report today,
but I'm going to put it off till tomorrow.
So you're going to do it tomorrow.
I'll do it tomorrow.
OK, so we've seen some really great
words and some really good phrases.
So now let's listen to
our dialogue for the last
time, and then we'll come
back and talk some more.
So Casey, how are things going
with the photos for the press kit?
Yeah.
I'd be meaning to talk to you about that.
I might need to ask for an
extension on that deadline.
I've had over a month
to get this finalized.
Why are things delayed?
Well, the thing is, we
ran into a lot of problems.
I'm not looking for excuses here.
I just want to get this finished on time.
I know, and I apologize for the delay.
But some things were
just beyond my control.
I had trouble booking the photographer,
and then Michael was sick for three weeks.
I couldn't include him in the photos,
and the design team lost all the files.
So I had to redo the pictures.
I'm not going to put
this off any longer, Casey.
I want those photos ASAP.
Well, Marco, do you think that
Casey's reasons for being late are good?
I think so, because it
wasn't really her fault,
the whole situation
with the photographer,
and then one of her coworkers
was sick for three weeks.
Yeah.
It's not really her fault, right?
Right, but maybe the boss
thinks that she's making excuses.
Yeah, maybe she's making excuses.
That's really common.
For example, when we
were kids, you would
say, "Oh, you know, my
dog ate my homework.
" Right, but that really
happened to me once.
Your dog ate your homework.
My cat ate my homework.
Your cat ate your homework.
Yeah.
And what did your teachers say?
Well, actually, I was a really good
student, so my teacher believed me.
Well, my teacher wouldn't have believed me.
Really?
No, no.
She would have called
my parents most likely.
My cat really did eat
my homework, and I just
left it on the table,
and it chewed it all up.
That's weird.
Why would your cat do that?
I don't know.
A lot of weird excuses out there.
Yeah.
I was abducted by aliens.
Uh-huh.
My mom accidentally
mailed my homework to Africa.
Really?
What happened to you?
Creative.
Writing.
Creative excuses.
Well, I want to hear from our listeners.
I want to know what excuses they've
used for being late with something.
So send us your excuses, send
us your comments and questions.
Go to our website at
EnglishPod.com, where Eric
and I are always there
to answer your questions.
That's right.
Marco, and this is an
elementary lesson, right?
Exactly.
But we also have
intermediates and upper
intermediates and advanced
lessons for you more
fluent English speakers.
Exactly.
So if you're listening to
us on iTunes, be sure to visit
our website and come see
what else we have to offer.
Well, I think we're out of time,
but until next time, it's goodbye.